Location: New York City
Telephone: +1 347 498-5369
Email: simongriffee@gmail.com
Portfolio: hypertexthero.com/work
Photographs: simongriffee.com/stories

## **Simon Griffee**

# **Summary**

Over a decade of professional experience, interaction & visual design work. Enjoy learning and absorbing information from different fields to help solve problems, keep brain whirring and, with any luck, pass on knowledge to future generations.

Traveled extensively around the world, living in Brazil, Tunisia, Italy, England and the United States. Speak and write in **English** and **Portuguese** fluently, **Italian** well, **French** and **Spanish** okay. Using these together with **visual** and **programming languages** have managed to:

- Reduce time people spend using computers while making the remaining more enjoyable.
- Make communication and cooperation between international organizations better.
- Help people with hands-on design, coding, editing and brainstorming.

Based in and usually ♥ New York City.

# **Experience**

#### **Information Systems Officer** (Designer & Developer)

Food and Agriculture Organization, United Nations, Rome, Italy & Worldwide, 2009–Present: Helped increase funding and the number of contracting parties to the International Plant Protection Convention and raise public awareness of its work while making people using computers there happier. Hands-on design and coding work from wireframes to production of websites and print media in both assigned and self-started projects. Organized photography groups and wine tasting.

Freelance Web & Graphic Designer · Hypertexthero, Worldwide, 2005–2009: Completed a variety of web and print projects for clients around the world, from large companies in London and internet startups in the Bay Area to non-profits and United Nations agencies in Rome.

**Web & Graphic Designer** · *Acotel Group S.p.A, Rome, Italy, 2003–2004:* Created the first web standards based website design project in Italy. Completed identity design projects, marketing and advertising campaigns.

**Designer** · European Artisans, Various, Rome, Italy, 1999–2003: Designer in an internet startup and for various clients.

### **Education**

Learned to work with computers using computer games. Learned graphic design from books, interfaces, posters and films by designers like Milton Glaser, Susan Kare, Robert Bringhurst and Saul Bass. Learned HTML and CSS by viewing the source of websites, searching with Google and reading Zeldman's Designing With Web Standards. Learned user experience, usability and accessibility principles from The Cluetrain Manifesto, Don't Make Me Think and Jacob Nielsen's Alertbox column. Learned photography by taking and looking at photographs. Learned to cook and eat in Italy. Learning Python, enjoyed meeting Alex Martelli in Florence in 2013.

Magnum Photos Workshops · Cortona 2011, Wolverhampton 2012, Paris 2013

Per Volquartz Workshop · Joshua Tree, California 2007

Stanford University, 2006 · Concept Design Workshop at Stanford University's d.school

Bournemouth University, 1996–1999 · B.A. with Honours in Creative Advertising

Arts University Bournemouth, 1997–1998 · City & Guilds Diploma with Distinction in Photography

#### **Interests**

Communication, information & free culture, photography, travel, independent web, open source & open internet, philosophy, art history, typography, nature, astronomy, music (play blues & rock guitar), computer simulations, vintage aeroplanes, basketball.

## **Skills & Tools**

**Visual design:** Typography and layout to make things beautiful and useful. Pens and paper, white and black boards, Sketch, Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign and Lightroom.

Interaction design and web development: Fast, simple interfaces and good writing over excessive style. Wireframing in HTML & CSS client-side code that usually ends up in production. Web browsers (Chrome and Firefox) and their developer tools, Textmate and a Terminal prompt. Have experience with Python and Django that is also used to edit hypertexthero.com on a local development server that is then published with rsync and version controlled with Git and GitHub. Also know a bit of Ruby and Jekyll, some Apache and Nginx configuration, a tiny bit of MySQL, PostgreSQL and SQLite, and a little Unix system administration. Currently learning Quartz Composer, Origami.

**Photography:** Candid photography, usually on the street using rangefinder and small cameras. Want a better camera for photography students and better editing software.